<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<prp:ObsProposal xmlns:ent="Alma/CommonEntity"
    xmlns:val="Alma/ValueTypes" xmlns:prp="Alma/ObsPrep/ObsProposal"
    xmlns:orv="Alma/ObsPrep/ObsReview"
    xmlns:ps="Alma/ObsPrep/ProjectStatus"
    xmlns:oat="Alma/ObsPrep/ObsAttachment"
    xmlns:prj="Alma/ObsPrep/ObsProject"
    xmlns:sbl="Alma/ObsPrep/SchedBlock"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    schemaVersion="13" revision="13" almatype="APDM::ObsProposal" xsi:type="prp:ObsProposal">
    <prj:ScienceGoal mode="Standard">
        <prj:name>Band 3 CO J=1-0</prj:name>
        <prj:note>Main science goals:
- Constrain photodissociation radius of CO (spatial resolution: 12m Array + ACA)
- Line-strength contrast with higher-J emission lines (high sensitivity) to constrain mass-loss rate

Additional science goals:
- Detection of (or upper limit for) C17O J=1-0
- Detect photodissociation product: CN
- Continuum to constrain flux from the cold dust component of the wind, and the grain size (through long-wavelength continuum slope/spectral index)</prj:note>
        <prj:estimatedTotalTime unit="min">650.813333365</prj:estimatedTotalTime>
        <prj:userPriority>0</prj:userPriority>
        <prj:requiredReceiverBands>ALMA_RB_03</prj:requiredReceiverBands>
        <prj:estimated12mTime unit="min">130.162666673</prj:estimated12mTime>
        <prj:estimated7mTime unit="min">260.325333346</prj:estimated7mTime>
        <prj:estimatedTPTime unit="min">520.650666692</prj:estimatedTPTime>
        <prj:estimatedACATime unit="min">520.650666692</prj:estimatedACATime>
        <prj:CalibrationSetupParameters selection="system"/>
        <prj:PerformanceParameters desiredSensitivityFrequencyMeasure="FinestResolution">
            <prj:desiredAngularResolution unit="arcsec" userUnit="arcsec">1.2</prj:desiredAngularResolution>
            <prj:desiredLargestScale unit="arcsec">40.0</prj:desiredLargestScale>
            <prj:desiredSensitivity unit="mJy" userUnit="mJy">1.6</prj:desiredSensitivity>
            <prj:desiredDynamicRange>1.0</prj:desiredDynamicRange>
            <prj:representativeFrequency unit="GHz">114.76170684187124</prj:representativeFrequency>
            <prj:useACA>true</prj:useACA>
            <prj:isTimeConstrained>false</prj:isTimeConstrained>
            <prj:useTP>true</prj:useTP>
            <prj:desiredSDSensitivity unit="Jy" userUnit="Jy">0.0</prj:desiredSDSensitivity>
            <prj:isPointSource>false</prj:isPointSource>
            <prj:desiredSensitivityReferenceFrequencyWidth unit="MHz" userUnit="MHz">0.0</prj:desiredSensitivityReferenceFrequencyWidth>
            <prj:needsMoreTime>false</prj:needsMoreTime>
            <prj:desiredACASensitivity unit="mJy" userUnit="Jy">10.104814276661767</prj:desiredACASensitivity>
            <prj:desiredTPSensitivity unit="Jy" userUnit="Jy">0.0231862027939031</prj:desiredTPSensitivity>
            <prj:isScheduleConstrained>false</prj:isScheduleConstrained>
            <prj:desiredTime unit="s">0.0</prj:desiredTime>
            <prj:TemporalParameters>
                <prj:startTime></prj:startTime>
                <prj:endTime></prj:endTime>
                <prj:allowedMargin unit="s">0.0</prj:allowedMargin>
                <prj:repeats>0</prj:repeats>
                <prj:lSTMin></prj:lSTMin>
                <prj:lSTMax></prj:lSTMax>
                <prj:note></prj:note>
                <prj:isAvoidConstraint>false</prj:isAvoidConstraint>
                <prj:priority>0</prj:priority>
                <prj:isFixedStart>false</prj:isFixedStart>
            </prj:TemporalParameters>
        </prj:PerformanceParameters>
        <prj:SpectralSetupParameters polarisation="DOUBLE" type="full">
            <prj:representativeFrequency unit="GHz">114.8</prj:representativeFrequency>
            <prj:userRepresentativeFrequency>false</prj:userRepresentativeFrequency>
            <prj:singleContinuumFrequency unit="GHz">0.0</prj:singleContinuumFrequency>
            <prj:ScienceSpectralWindow groupResourceUse="FULL">
                <prj:index>0</prj:index>
                <prj:AdvancedWindowSetup smoothingFunction="HANNING">
                    <prj:smoothingFactor>16</prj:smoothingFactor>
                    <prj:oversampling>false</prj:oversampling>
                    <prj:addedSensitivity>false</prj:addedSensitivity>
                    <prj:useImage>false</prj:useImage>
                    <prj:useThis>true</prj:useThis>
                </prj:AdvancedWindowSetup>
                <prj:transitionName>CN v=0 N=1-0, J=3/2-1/2, F=5/2-3/2</prj:transitionName>
                <prj:centerFrequency unit="GHz">113.49097019999999</prj:centerFrequency>
                <prj:bandWidth unit="MHz" userUnit="GHz">250.0</prj:bandWidth>
                <prj:spectralResolution unit="kHz" userUnit="GHz">61.03515625000001</prj:spectralResolution>
                <prj:groupIndex>2</prj:groupIndex>
                <prj:isSkyFrequency>false</prj:isSkyFrequency>
                <prj:splatalogId>28161</prj:splatalogId>
                <prj:representativeWindow>false</prj:representativeWindow>
            </prj:ScienceSpectralWindow>
            <prj:ScienceSpectralWindow groupResourceUse="FULL">
                <prj:index>0</prj:index>
                <prj:AdvancedWindowSetup smoothingFunction="HANNING">
                    <prj:smoothingFactor>16</prj:smoothingFactor>
                    <prj:oversampling>false</prj:oversampling>
                    <prj:addedSensitivity>false</prj:addedSensitivity>
                    <prj:useImage>false</prj:useImage>
                    <prj:useThis>true</prj:useThis>
                </prj:AdvancedWindowSetup>
                <prj:transitionName>C17O J=1-0</prj:transitionName>
                <prj:centerFrequency unit="GHz">113.0</prj:centerFrequency>
                <prj:bandWidth unit="MHz" userUnit="GHz">250.0</prj:bandWidth>
                <prj:spectralResolution unit="kHz" userUnit="GHz">61.03515625000001</prj:spectralResolution>
                <prj:groupIndex>1</prj:groupIndex>
                <prj:isSkyFrequency>false</prj:isSkyFrequency>
                <prj:splatalogId>3768368</prj:splatalogId>
                <prj:representativeWindow>false</prj:representativeWindow>
            </prj:ScienceSpectralWindow>
            <prj:ScienceSpectralWindow groupResourceUse="FULL">
                <prj:index>0</prj:index>
                <prj:AdvancedWindowSetup smoothingFunction="HANNING">
                    <prj:smoothingFactor>1</prj:smoothingFactor>
                    <prj:oversampling>false</prj:oversampling>
                    <prj:addedSensitivity>false</prj:addedSensitivity>
                    <prj:useImage>false</prj:useImage>
                    <prj:useThis>true</prj:useThis>
                </prj:AdvancedWindowSetup>
                <prj:transitionName>Continuum</prj:transitionName>
                <prj:centerFrequency unit="GHz">114.0</prj:centerFrequency>
                <prj:bandWidth unit="MHz" userUnit="GHz">2000.0</prj:bandWidth>
                <prj:spectralResolution unit="MHz" userUnit="GHz">15.625</prj:spectralResolution>
                <prj:groupIndex>3</prj:groupIndex>
                <prj:isSkyFrequency>false</prj:isSkyFrequency>
                <prj:splatalogId>3974740</prj:splatalogId>
                <prj:representativeWindow>false</prj:representativeWindow>
            </prj:ScienceSpectralWindow>
            <prj:ScienceSpectralWindow groupResourceUse="FULL">
                <prj:index>0</prj:index>
                <prj:AdvancedWindowSetup smoothingFunction="HANNING">
                    <prj:smoothingFactor>16</prj:smoothingFactor>
                    <prj:oversampling>false</prj:oversampling>
                    <prj:addedSensitivity>false</prj:addedSensitivity>
                    <prj:useImage>false</prj:useImage>
                    <prj:useThis>true</prj:useThis>
                </prj:AdvancedWindowSetup>
                <prj:transitionName>CO v=0 1-0</prj:transitionName>
                <prj:centerFrequency unit="GHz">114.8</prj:centerFrequency>
                <prj:bandWidth unit="MHz" userUnit="GHz">250.0</prj:bandWidth>
                <prj:spectralResolution unit="kHz" userUnit="GHz">61.03515625000001</prj:spectralResolution>
                <prj:groupIndex>0</prj:groupIndex>
                <prj:isSkyFrequency>false</prj:isSkyFrequency>
                <prj:splatalogId>3768098</prj:splatalogId>
                <prj:representativeWindow>true</prj:representativeWindow>
            </prj:ScienceSpectralWindow>
        </prj:SpectralSetupParameters>
        <prj:TargetParameters solarSystemObject="Unspecified" type="F_MultiplePoints">
            <prj:sourceName>OH30.1-0.7</prj:sourceName>
            <prj:sourceCoordinates system="J2000" type="ABSOLUTE">
                <val:longitude unit="deg">282.174625</val:longitude>
                <val:latitude unit="deg">-2.841193888888889</val:latitude>
                <val:fieldName>None</val:fieldName>
            </prj:sourceCoordinates>
            <prj:pmRA unit="mas/yr">0.0</prj:pmRA>
            <prj:pmDec unit="mas/yr">0.0</prj:pmDec>
            <prj:parallax unit="mas">0.0</prj:parallax>
            <prj:nonSiderealMotion>false</prj:nonSiderealMotion>
            <prj:sourceEphemeris></prj:sourceEphemeris>
            <prj:sourceVelocity referenceSystem="lsrk" dopplerCalcType="RADIO">
                <val:centerVelocity unit="km/s">100.0</val:centerVelocity>
            </prj:sourceVelocity>
            <prj:index>-1</prj:index>
            <prj:ExpectedProperties>
                <prj:expectedPeakFluxDensity unit="mJy">0.7</prj:expectedPeakFluxDensity>
                <prj:desiredPolarizationPercentage>0.0</prj:desiredPolarizationPercentage>
                <prj:expectedLineWidth unit="GHz" userUnit="km/s">0.013724746789193897</prj:expectedLineWidth>
                <prj:referenceFrequency unit="GHz">114.76170684187124</prj:referenceFrequency>
                <prj:expectedPeakLineFluxDensity unit="mJy">8.0</prj:expectedPeakLineFluxDensity>
                <prj:expectedSpectralDynamicRange>0.0</prj:expectedSpectralDynamicRange>
                <prj:expectedImageDynamicRange>0.0</prj:expectedImageDynamicRange>
                <prj:desiredLinePolarizationPercentage>0.0</prj:desiredLinePolarizationPercentage>
            </prj:ExpectedProperties>
            <prj:isMosaic>false</prj:isMosaic>
            <prj:SinglePoint>
                <prj:name></prj:name>
                <prj:centre system="J2000" type="RELATIVE">
                    <val:longitude unit="arcsec">0.0</val:longitude>
                    <val:latitude unit="arcsec">0.0</val:latitude>
                    <val:fieldName>OH30.1-0.7-1</val:fieldName>
                </prj:centre>
            </prj:SinglePoint>
        </prj:TargetParameters>
        <prj:TechnicalJustification>
            <prj:justificationText>The expected flux density is estimated from 3D radiative transfer models that reproduce the single-dish and Herschel PACS and SPIRE for CO lines. The goal is 1) to constrain the size of the superwind by looking at emission in the outer wind compared to the emission in the inner wind, 2) to determine the photodissociation radius through the CO J=1-0 line, and 3) distinguish between variable mass-loss history and photodissociation in the wind by combining the measured photodissociation radius with resolved dust continuum observations in Band 6 and 7. Figure 2 in the Science Case description shows ALMA OST processed images of the CO J=1-0 line and highlights the need for the requested sensitivities.

Three scenarios were tested: 
1) continuous high mass-loss-rate superwind
2) a tenuous lower mass-loss-rate wind increasing to a high, current mass-loss-rate superwind
3) continuous high mass-loss-rate superwind, with enhanced photodissociation

The density profiles associated with these three scenarios are:
1) a smooth r^-2 density profile
2) a smooth r^-2 density profile with a density decrease by one order of magnitude at 3375 AU
3) a smooth r^-2 density profile, cut off at a much closer distance from the stellar surface

To take into account several model dependencies, especially in scenario 2, we have always assumed worst-case scenarios in terms of flux contrast between high and low mass-loss-rate regimes, as well as the radius at which the density decreases. The goal is then to reach sensitivities that detect flux in the outer, tenuous wind to distinguish between the three suggested scenarios. 

For CO J=1-0 in the first two scenarios at r &gt; 3375 AU (density step in scenario 2), we processed the radiative transfer models with the ALMA OST for the central velocity component. This results in (see Figure 2 in the Science Case):
1) 150 mJy/beam
2) &lt; 10 mJy/beam
using a synthesised beam size of 1.2''. We ask for an RMS of 1.6 mJy/beam, so that we can trace CO emission in the outer wind and detect where photodissociation destroys CO with a 5-sigma detection limit. Not detecting the tenuous outer wind at all implies a small superwind size and supports scenario 2. The requested sensitivity guarantees detecting emission from the superwind itself at the midpoint of the image, with 80 mJy/beam &lt; F_SW &lt; 270 mJy/beam.

The bandwidth of the CO J=1-0 line is used in the sensitivity calculation. The spectral resolution does not have to be high, since the goal is to detect the line and spatially resolve it. The line is not expected to show any complex spectral structure, as shown by single-dish observations. 14 spectral resolution elements is therefore enough, and allows a higher detection limit.

For the other lines in this spectral setup, spatial resolution is not important, and a 3-sigma detection of the central component is enough to reach the additional science goals. Since we already perform a deep integration for the tenuous CO 1-0 emission, the other lines are likely to be detected if they are sufficiently abundant (in the case of the chemical daughter species CN), or provide solid upper flux limits (in the case of C17O, to constrain nucleosynthesis models).

The peak continuum flux density is estimated from dust radiative-transfer models reproducing the SED of the source. Images were calculated at 2.6 mm, and ray-traced according to a resolution equivalent with the synthesised beam size. The peak of the flux distribution results in:
- 1 mJy/beam for scenario 1
- 0.7 mJy/beam for scenario 2 and 3
The requested sensitivity for the CO J=1-0 line is high enough to detect the continuum emission. This places strong constraints on the long-wavelength fluxes of this source, which were not available before without interstellar background contamination. 

The requested angular resolution for this setting is too low to detect the outer part of the dusty wind, so we request a continuum flux density of 0.7 mJy/beam.</prj:justificationText>
            <prj:justificationKey>ED_SENSITIVITY</prj:justificationKey>
        </prj:TechnicalJustification>
        <prj:TechnicalJustification>
            <prj:justificationText>The correlator setup is focused on the primary goals of detecting 
- spatially resolved CO J=1-0 line emission
- dust continuum emission

Hence, one baseband is set for the CO J=1-0 line and one baseband is set for the dust continuum (at the lowest possible spectral resolution). The two extra basebands are set for additional science, i.e. a line of CN and of HNO (to constrain photodissociation models of AGB winds), and of C17O (to provide a constraint for nucleosynthesis models).

The CO J=1-0 line has 14 spectral resolution elements per line width. The main goal is to detect the line and spatially resolve it. The spectral structure is not expected to be complex (as derived from single-dish observations), so we ask for a spectral resolution that resolves the overall line shape. We also ask for the maximum spectral averaging to keep the data rate low. The window width of ~600 km/s provides enough continuum, given that the line width is known to be 36 km/s (for a wind expansion velocity of 18 km/s).

The additional-science lines of CN and C17O, have not been detected before and the deep integration required for the CO line, ensures that these observations provide reliable upper limits, if not detections. A low spectral resolution is enough, and ensures highest likelihood of detection. </prj:justificationText>
            <prj:justificationKey>ED_CORRELATOR</prj:justificationKey>
        </prj:TechnicalJustification>
        <prj:TechnicalJustification>
            <prj:justificationText>The CO J=1-0 line is our primary concern for this science goal. We base the requested angular scales on:
1) the predicted superwind radii from the literature (going from r = 1700 AU up to r &gt; 10000 AU, i.e. diameters going from 3400 AU up to d &gt; 20000 AU)
2) the line formation region, estimated from 1d and 3d radiative-transfer models
3) the CO photodissociation radius from several models

Compared to the CO J=2-1 and CO J=3-2 lines, we follow a different approach to determine the required angular scales for the CO J=1-0 line. The main goal is to detect the tenuous outer wind itself, making sensitivity even more important. We therefore request a lower spatial resolution to further increase the detection limit of weak CO J=1-0 emission, while still resolving the outer, tenuous wind. We will not resolve the superwind itself (in the worst-case scenario), but integrated CO emission profiles can still contribute to constraining the superwind size, alongside the CO J=2-1 and CO J=3-2 lines. 

We request an angular resolution of 1.2 arcsec. To convert this number to a linear scale, we take into account the uncertain distance to the source. The distance from SED modelling is estimated to be 2.0-2.4 kpc. The distance from 1612-MHz OH maser phase lag measurements is estimated to be ~4.0 kpc. 

This translates to different sizes in the wind depending on distance:
- At 2.0 kpc, 1.2 arcsec is 2400 AU.
- At 4.0 kpc, 1.2 arcsec is 4800 AU.
Based on radiative transfer models, these are typical scales of CO J=1-0 line formation regions. 

For the maximum recoverable scale, we take into account the model with the largest predicted CO photodissociation radius at superwind mass-loss rates (Mamon et al 1988): ~ 80000 AU. This also covers the largest available prediction of the superwind radius at r &gt; 20000 AU.
- At 2.0 kpc, 80000 AU is 40 arcsec.
- At 4.0 kpc, 80000 AU is 20 arcsec.
We request a maximum recoverable scale of 40 arcsec.

The requested angular scales will not resolve the dust component of the superwind in this setting, and we do not need to. We can resolve the dust component in the other science goals, at shorter wavelengths. An unresolved detection of the dust component in this setting still provides additional, new science through continuum photometry at 2.6 mm. 

Additional science:
The spatial resolution of the CO emission drives the chosen angular scales. For all of the additional science (molecular lines), detection is the main goal. We do not expect to resolve this emission with the requested setting, and don't need to. 

Background:
The source lies in the galactic plane and is therefore affected by interstellar background contamination. However, the interstellar background is expected to be homogeneous on a scale of 40 arcseconds, based on position-switching IRAM observations with 20 arcseconds offset in four directions with respect to the source. ALMA observations should not be affected, as this background will be resolved out.</prj:justificationText>
            <prj:justificationKey>ED_ANGULAR_RESOLUTION</prj:justificationKey>
        </prj:TechnicalJustification>
    </prj:ScienceGoal>
    <prj:ScienceGoal mode="Standard">
        <prj:name>Band 7 CO J=3-2</prj:name>
        <prj:note>Main science goals:
- Constrain CO emitting region of the outer, low mass-loss-rate region of the wind (spatial resolution: 12m Array + ACA)
- Constrain the superwind size and density in CO
- Continuum to constrain the size of the dust conmponent of the superwind
- Line-strength contrast with J=1-0 and J=3-2 emission lines to detect possible change in density profile (high sensitivity) and constrain the mass-loss rate

Additional science goals:
- Measure SiO J=8-7
- Detection of (or upper limit for) C17O J=3-2
- Constrain flux from the cold dust component of the wind, and the grain size (through long-wavelength continuum slope/spectral index)

</prj:note>
        <prj:estimatedTotalTime unit="min">251.301</prj:estimatedTotalTime>
        <prj:userPriority>0</prj:userPriority>
        <prj:requiredReceiverBands>ALMA_RB_07</prj:requiredReceiverBands>
        <prj:estimated12mTime unit="min">83.767</prj:estimated12mTime>
        <prj:estimated7mTime unit="min">167.534</prj:estimated7mTime>
        <prj:estimatedTPTime unit="s">0.0</prj:estimatedTPTime>
        <prj:estimatedACATime unit="min">167.534</prj:estimatedACATime>
        <prj:CalibrationSetupParameters selection="system"/>
        <prj:PerformanceParameters desiredSensitivityFrequencyMeasure="FinestResolution">
            <prj:desiredAngularResolution unit="arcsec" userUnit="arcsec">0.425</prj:desiredAngularResolution>
            <prj:desiredLargestScale unit="arcsec">10.0</prj:desiredLargestScale>
            <prj:desiredSensitivity unit="mJy" userUnit="mJy">1.4</prj:desiredSensitivity>
            <prj:desiredDynamicRange>1.0</prj:desiredDynamicRange>
            <prj:representativeFrequency unit="GHz">345.68064487347254</prj:representativeFrequency>
            <prj:useACA>true</prj:useACA>
            <prj:isTimeConstrained>false</prj:isTimeConstrained>
            <prj:useTP>false</prj:useTP>
            <prj:desiredSDSensitivity unit="Jy" userUnit="Jy">0.0</prj:desiredSDSensitivity>
            <prj:isPointSource>false</prj:isPointSource>
            <prj:desiredSensitivityReferenceFrequencyWidth unit="MHz" userUnit="MHz">0.0</prj:desiredSensitivityReferenceFrequencyWidth>
            <prj:needsMoreTime>false</prj:needsMoreTime>
            <prj:desiredACASensitivity unit="mJy" userUnit="Jy">8.477727650114911</prj:desiredACASensitivity>
            <prj:desiredTPSensitivity unit="Jy" userUnit="Jy">0.02028792744466521</prj:desiredTPSensitivity>
            <prj:isScheduleConstrained>false</prj:isScheduleConstrained>
            <prj:desiredTime unit="s">0.0</prj:desiredTime>
            <prj:TemporalParameters>
                <prj:startTime></prj:startTime>
                <prj:endTime></prj:endTime>
                <prj:allowedMargin unit="s">0.0</prj:allowedMargin>
                <prj:repeats>0</prj:repeats>
                <prj:lSTMin></prj:lSTMin>
                <prj:lSTMax></prj:lSTMax>
                <prj:note></prj:note>
                <prj:isAvoidConstraint>false</prj:isAvoidConstraint>
                <prj:priority>0</prj:priority>
                <prj:isFixedStart>false</prj:isFixedStart>
            </prj:TemporalParameters>
        </prj:PerformanceParameters>
        <prj:SpectralSetupParameters polarisation="DOUBLE" type="full">
            <prj:representativeFrequency unit="GHz">345.79599</prj:representativeFrequency>
            <prj:userRepresentativeFrequency>false</prj:userRepresentativeFrequency>
            <prj:singleContinuumFrequency unit="GHz">0.0</prj:singleContinuumFrequency>
            <prj:ScienceSpectralWindow groupResourceUse="HALF">
                <prj:index>0</prj:index>
                <prj:AdvancedWindowSetup smoothingFunction="HANNING">
                    <prj:smoothingFactor>16</prj:smoothingFactor>
                    <prj:oversampling>false</prj:oversampling>
                    <prj:addedSensitivity>false</prj:addedSensitivity>
                    <prj:useImage>false</prj:useImage>
                    <prj:useThis>true</prj:useThis>
                </prj:AdvancedWindowSetup>
                <prj:transitionName>C17O J=3-2</prj:transitionName>
                <prj:centerFrequency unit="GHz">337.061104</prj:centerFrequency>
                <prj:bandWidth unit="MHz" userUnit="GHz">500.0</prj:bandWidth>
                <prj:spectralResolution unit="kHz" userUnit="GHz">244.14062500000003</prj:spectralResolution>
                <prj:groupIndex>3</prj:groupIndex>
                <prj:isSkyFrequency>false</prj:isSkyFrequency>
                <prj:splatalogId>3768370</prj:splatalogId>
                <prj:representativeWindow>false</prj:representativeWindow>
            </prj:ScienceSpectralWindow>
            <prj:ScienceSpectralWindow groupResourceUse="FULL">
                <prj:index>0</prj:index>
                <prj:AdvancedWindowSetup smoothingFunction="HANNING">
                    <prj:smoothingFactor>16</prj:smoothingFactor>
                    <prj:oversampling>false</prj:oversampling>
                    <prj:addedSensitivity>false</prj:addedSensitivity>
                    <prj:useImage>false</prj:useImage>
                    <prj:useThis>true</prj:useThis>
                </prj:AdvancedWindowSetup>
                <prj:transitionName>SiO v=0 8-7</prj:transitionName>
                <prj:centerFrequency unit="GHz">347.3305786</prj:centerFrequency>
                <prj:bandWidth unit="MHz" userUnit="GHz">1000.0</prj:bandWidth>
                <prj:spectralResolution unit="kHz" userUnit="GHz">244.14062500000003</prj:spectralResolution>
                <prj:groupIndex>1</prj:groupIndex>
                <prj:isSkyFrequency>false</prj:isSkyFrequency>
                <prj:splatalogId>6962458</prj:splatalogId>
                <prj:representativeWindow>false</prj:representativeWindow>
            </prj:ScienceSpectralWindow>
            <prj:ScienceSpectralWindow groupResourceUse="FULL">
                <prj:index>0</prj:index>
                <prj:AdvancedWindowSetup smoothingFunction="HANNING">
                    <prj:smoothingFactor>1</prj:smoothingFactor>
                    <prj:oversampling>false</prj:oversampling>
                    <prj:addedSensitivity>false</prj:addedSensitivity>
                    <prj:useImage>false</prj:useImage>
                    <prj:useThis>true</prj:useThis>
                </prj:AdvancedWindowSetup>
                <prj:transitionName>Continuum</prj:transitionName>
                <prj:centerFrequency unit="GHz">335.1117812581056</prj:centerFrequency>
                <prj:bandWidth unit="MHz" userUnit="GHz">2000.0</prj:bandWidth>
                <prj:spectralResolution unit="MHz" userUnit="GHz">15.625</prj:spectralResolution>
                <prj:groupIndex>2</prj:groupIndex>
                <prj:isSkyFrequency>false</prj:isSkyFrequency>
                <prj:splatalogId>3951103</prj:splatalogId>
                <prj:representativeWindow>false</prj:representativeWindow>
            </prj:ScienceSpectralWindow>
            <prj:ScienceSpectralWindow groupResourceUse="HALF">
                <prj:index>0</prj:index>
                <prj:AdvancedWindowSetup smoothingFunction="HANNING">
                    <prj:smoothingFactor>16</prj:smoothingFactor>
                    <prj:oversampling>false</prj:oversampling>
                    <prj:addedSensitivity>false</prj:addedSensitivity>
                    <prj:useImage>false</prj:useImage>
                    <prj:useThis>true</prj:useThis>
                </prj:AdvancedWindowSetup>
                <prj:transitionName>CO v=0 3-2</prj:transitionName>
                <prj:centerFrequency unit="GHz">345.79599</prj:centerFrequency>
                <prj:bandWidth unit="MHz" userUnit="GHz">500.0</prj:bandWidth>
                <prj:spectralResolution unit="kHz" userUnit="GHz">244.14062500000003</prj:spectralResolution>
                <prj:groupIndex>0</prj:groupIndex>
                <prj:isSkyFrequency>false</prj:isSkyFrequency>
                <prj:splatalogId>3768104</prj:splatalogId>
                <prj:representativeWindow>true</prj:representativeWindow>
            </prj:ScienceSpectralWindow>
        </prj:SpectralSetupParameters>
        <prj:TargetParameters solarSystemObject="Unspecified" type="F_MultiplePoints">
            <prj:sourceName>OH30.1-0.7</prj:sourceName>
            <prj:sourceCoordinates system="J2000" type="ABSOLUTE">
                <val:longitude unit="deg">282.174625</val:longitude>
                <val:latitude unit="deg">-2.841194</val:latitude>
                <val:fieldName>None</val:fieldName>
            </prj:sourceCoordinates>
            <prj:pmRA unit="mas/yr">0.0</prj:pmRA>
            <prj:pmDec unit="mas/yr">0.0</prj:pmDec>
            <prj:parallax unit="mas">0.0</prj:parallax>
            <prj:nonSiderealMotion>false</prj:nonSiderealMotion>
            <prj:sourceEphemeris></prj:sourceEphemeris>
            <prj:sourceVelocity referenceSystem="lsrk" dopplerCalcType="RADIO">
                <val:centerVelocity unit="km/s">100.0</val:centerVelocity>
            </prj:sourceVelocity>
            <prj:index>-1</prj:index>
            <prj:ExpectedProperties>
                <prj:expectedPeakFluxDensity unit="mJy">0.4</prj:expectedPeakFluxDensity>
                <prj:desiredPolarizationPercentage>0.0</prj:desiredPolarizationPercentage>
                <prj:expectedLineWidth unit="GHz" userUnit="km/s">0.04151039455250409</prj:expectedLineWidth>
                <prj:referenceFrequency unit="GHz">345.68064487347254</prj:referenceFrequency>
                <prj:expectedPeakLineFluxDensity unit="mJy">5.0</prj:expectedPeakLineFluxDensity>
                <prj:expectedSpectralDynamicRange>0.0</prj:expectedSpectralDynamicRange>
                <prj:expectedImageDynamicRange>0.0</prj:expectedImageDynamicRange>
                <prj:desiredLinePolarizationPercentage>0.0</prj:desiredLinePolarizationPercentage>
            </prj:ExpectedProperties>
            <prj:isMosaic>false</prj:isMosaic>
            <prj:SinglePoint>
                <prj:name></prj:name>
                <prj:centre system="J2000" type="RELATIVE">
                    <val:longitude unit="arcsec">0.0</val:longitude>
                    <val:latitude unit="arcsec">0.0</val:latitude>
                    <val:fieldName>OH30.1-0.7-1</val:fieldName>
                </prj:centre>
            </prj:SinglePoint>
        </prj:TargetParameters>
        <prj:TechnicalJustification>
            <prj:justificationText>The expected flux density is estimated from 3D radiative transfer models that reproduce the single-dish and Herschel PACS and SPIRE for CO lines. The goal is 1) to constrain the size of the superwind by looking at emission in the outer wind compared to the emission in the inner wind, and 2) distinguish between variable mass-loss history and photodissociation in the wind by combining the measured photodissociation radius in CO J=1-0 with resolved dust continuum observations in Band 7. 

Three scenarios were tested: 
1) continuous high mass-loss-rate superwind
2) a tenuous lower mass-loss-rate wind increasing to a high, current mass-loss-rate superwind
3) continuous high mass-loss-rate superwind, with enhanced photodissociation

The density profiles associated with these three scenarios are:
1) a smooth r^-2 density profile
2) a smooth r^-2 density profile with a density decrease by one order of magnitude at 3375 AU
3) a smooth r^-2 density profile, cut off at a much closer distance from the stellar surface

To take into account several model dependencies, especially in scenario 2, we have always assumed worst-case scenarios in terms of flux contrast between high and low mass-loss-rate regimes, as well as the radius at which the density decreases. The goal is then to reach sensitivities that detect flux in the outer wind in scenario 1, but not in scenario 2. 

For CO J=3-2 in scenario 1, predicted flux estimates after ALMA OST processing are:
- at the density step radius of 3375 AU: 100 mJy/beam
- in the outer wind at r &gt; 3375 AU, smooth decrease from 100 mJy/beam to 5 mJy/beam
using a synthesised beam size of 0.425''. In scenarios 2 and 3, the flux in the outer wind would simply not be detected. The predicted flux at the midpoint of the image is 1100 mJy/beam.

To detect the emission from the outer wind far enough (up to 10000 AU - see justification angular scales), we request a sensitivity of 1.40 mJy. This leads to an SNR of ~ 3 for the outermost parts of the wind that are still detectable, and higher SNR at r &lt; 10000 AU. 

The bandwidth of the CO J=3-2 line is used in the sensitivity calculation. The spectral resolution does not have to be high, since the goal is to detect the line and spatially resolve it. The line is not expected to show any complex spectral structure, as shown by single-dish observations. 10 spectral resolution elements is therefore enough, and allows a higher detection limit.

For the other lines in this spectral setup, spatial resolution is not important, and a 3-sigma detection of the central component is enough to reach the additional science goals. Since we already perform a deep integration for the tenuous CO 3-2 emission, the other lines are likely to be detected if they are sufficiently abundant (in the case of SiO), or provide solid upper flux limits (in the case of the C17O).

The peak continuum flux density is estimated from dust radiative-transfer models reproducing the SED of the source. Images were calculated at 867 micron, and ray-traced according to a resolution equivalent with the synthesised beam size of 0.425 arcsec. The peak of the flux distribution results in:
- 6.6 mJy/beam for scenario 1 and 3
- 4.5 mJy/beam for scenario 2
The requested sensitivity for the CO J=3-2 line is high enough to detect the continuum emission. This places strong constraints on the long-wavelength fluxes of this source, which were not available before without interstellar background contamination. 

At 1.7 arcseconds from the center of the image, dust emission amounts to
- 0.40 mJy/beam for scenario 1
- 0.025 mJy/beam for scenario 2 and 3
With the requested sensitivity of the CO J=3-2 line, we can still detect continuum flux 1.7 arcsec from the central source in scenario 1, while a non-detection would result from scenarios 2 and 3. This constrains the size of the dust component of the superwind, and therefore distinguishes between scenarios 2 and 3. Hence, we request a continuum flux density of 0.40 mJy/beam.</prj:justificationText>
            <prj:justificationKey>ED_SENSITIVITY</prj:justificationKey>
        </prj:TechnicalJustification>
        <prj:TechnicalJustification>
            <prj:justificationText>The correlator setup is focused on the primary goals of detecting 
- spatially resolved CO J=3-2 line emission
- dust continuum emission

Hence, one baseband is set for the CO J=3-2 line and one baseband is set for the dust continuum (at the lowest possible spectral resolution). The two extra basebands are set for additional science, i.e. a line of HNO (to constrain photodissociation models of AGB winds), and of C17O (to provide a constraint for nucleosynthesis models).

The CO J=3-2 line has 10 spectral resolution elements per line width. The main goal is to detect the line and spatially resolve it. The spectral structure is not expected to be complex (as derived from single-dish observations), so we ask for a spectral resolution that resolves the overall line shape. We also ask for the maximum spectral averaging to keep the data rate low. The window width of ~400 km/s provides enough continuum, given that the line width is known to be 36 km/s (for a wind expansion velocity of 18 km/s).

The additional-science line C17O, has not been detected before and the deep integration required for the CO line, ensures that these observations provide reliable upper limits, if not detections. A low spectral resolution is enough, and ensures highest likelihood of detection. Finally, one SiO line is included in the spectral setup as it is a common molecule in oxygen-rich outflows. </prj:justificationText>
            <prj:justificationKey>ED_CORRELATOR</prj:justificationKey>
        </prj:TechnicalJustification>
        <prj:TechnicalJustification>
            <prj:justificationText>The CO J=3-2 line is our primary concern for this science goal. We base the requested angular scales on:
1) the predicted superwind radii from the literature (going from r = 1700 AU up to r &gt; 6000 AU, i.e. diameters going from 3400 AU up to d &gt; 12000 AU)
2) the line formation region, estimated from 1d and 3d radiative-transfer models

To resolve the superwind radii, we need a beam size of at least 3400 AU. This is balanced by the need to detect weak emission in the outer parts of the wind. Because the size of the superwind itself, and not the structure within the superwind, is the primary goal, we request beam sizes so that the minimum resolution of the superwind on the sky is 4 in the worst case scenario of large distance and smallest predicted superwind size. Hence, we request the beam size equivalent of 1700 AU.

From radiative transfer models, the emission for the CO J=3-2 is predicted to be too weak to be detected beyond a radius of at least 10000 AU. To ensure we do not miss out on any flux at larger distances, we request a maximum recoverable scale of 20000 AU (diameter = 2*r = 2*10000 AU). 

To convert these numbers to angular scales, we take into account the uncertain distance to the source. The distance from SED modelling is estimated to be 2.0-2.4 kpc. The distance from 1612-MHz OH maser phase lag measurements is estimated to be ~4.0 kpc. 

Resolution:
- At 2.0 kpc, 1700 AU is 850 mas.
- At 4.0 kpc, 1700 AU is 425 mas.
We request 425 mas angular resolution.

Largest scale: 
- At 2.0 kpc, 20000 AU is 10 arcsec.
- At 4.0 kpc, 20000 AU is 5 arcsec.
We request a maximum recoverable scale of 10 arcsec.

The requested angular scales also allow to resolve the dust component of the superwind, and thus determine the superwind size in the dust. 

Additional science:
The spatial resolution of the CO emission drives the chosen angular scales. For all of the additional science (molecular lines), detection is the main goal. We do not expect to resolve this emission with the requested setting, and don't need to. 

Background:
The source lies in the galactic plane and is therefore affected by interstellar background contamination. However, the interstellar background is expected to be homogeneous on a scale of 40 arcseconds, based on position-switching IRAM observations with 20 arcseconds offset in four directions with respect to the source. ALMA observations should not be affected, as this background will be resolved out.</prj:justificationText>
            <prj:justificationKey>ED_ANGULAR_RESOLUTION</prj:justificationKey>
        </prj:TechnicalJustification>
    </prj:ScienceGoal>
    <prj:ScienceGoal mode="Standard">
        <prj:name>Band 6 CO J=2-1</prj:name>
        <prj:note>Main science goals:
- Constrain CO emitting region of the outer, low mass-loss-rate region of the wind (spatial resolution: 12m Array + ACA)
- Constrain the superwind size and density in CO
- Continuum to constrain the size of the dust component of the superwind
- Line-strength contrast with J=1-0 and J=2-1 emission lines to detect possible change in density profile (high sensitivity) and constrain the mass-loss rate


Additional science goals:
- Detect photodissociation product: CN
- Constrain flux from the cold dust component of the wind, and the grain size (through long-wavelength continuum slope/spectral index)
- Detection of an SO and a CS line</prj:note>
        <prj:estimatedTotalTime unit="min">244.55433330999998</prj:estimatedTotalTime>
        <prj:userPriority>0</prj:userPriority>
        <prj:requiredReceiverBands>ALMA_RB_06</prj:requiredReceiverBands>
        <prj:estimated12mTime unit="min">104.80899998999999</prj:estimated12mTime>
        <prj:estimated7mTime unit="min">139.74533332</prj:estimated7mTime>
        <prj:estimatedTPTime unit="s">0.0</prj:estimatedTPTime>
        <prj:estimatedACATime unit="min">139.74533332</prj:estimatedACATime>
        <prj:CalibrationSetupParameters selection="system"/>
        <prj:PerformanceParameters desiredSensitivityFrequencyMeasure="FinestResolution">
            <prj:desiredAngularResolution unit="arcsec" userUnit="arcsec">0.425</prj:desiredAngularResolution>
            <prj:desiredLargestScale unit="arcsec">15.0</prj:desiredLargestScale>
            <prj:desiredSensitivity unit="mJy" userUnit="mJy">1.2</prj:desiredSensitivity>
            <prj:desiredDynamicRange>1.0</prj:desiredDynamicRange>
            <prj:representativeFrequency unit="GHz">230.4611008006212</prj:representativeFrequency>
            <prj:useACA>true</prj:useACA>
            <prj:isTimeConstrained>false</prj:isTimeConstrained>
            <prj:useTP>false</prj:useTP>
            <prj:desiredSDSensitivity unit="Jy" userUnit="Jy">0.0</prj:desiredSDSensitivity>
            <prj:isPointSource>false</prj:isPointSource>
            <prj:desiredSensitivityReferenceFrequencyWidth unit="MHz" userUnit="MHz">0.0</prj:desiredSensitivityReferenceFrequencyWidth>
            <prj:needsMoreTime>false</prj:needsMoreTime>
            <prj:desiredACASensitivity unit="mJy" userUnit="Jy">7.4598687917562305</prj:desiredACASensitivity>
            <prj:desiredTPSensitivity unit="Jy" userUnit="Jy">0.01738965209542732</prj:desiredTPSensitivity>
            <prj:isScheduleConstrained>false</prj:isScheduleConstrained>
            <prj:desiredTime unit="min">0.0</prj:desiredTime>
        </prj:PerformanceParameters>
        <prj:SpectralSetupParameters polarisation="DOUBLE" type="full">
            <prj:representativeFrequency unit="GHz">230.538</prj:representativeFrequency>
            <prj:userRepresentativeFrequency>false</prj:userRepresentativeFrequency>
            <prj:singleContinuumFrequency unit="GHz">0.0</prj:singleContinuumFrequency>
            <prj:ScienceSpectralWindow groupResourceUse="HALF">
                <prj:index>0</prj:index>
                <prj:AdvancedWindowSetup smoothingFunction="HANNING">
                    <prj:smoothingFactor>16</prj:smoothingFactor>
                    <prj:oversampling>false</prj:oversampling>
                    <prj:addedSensitivity>false</prj:addedSensitivity>
                    <prj:useImage>false</prj:useImage>
                    <prj:useThis>true</prj:useThis>
                </prj:AdvancedWindowSetup>
                <prj:transitionName>SO 3? v=0 2(3)-3(2)</prj:transitionName>
                <prj:centerFrequency unit="GHz">246.4045881</prj:centerFrequency>
                <prj:bandWidth unit="MHz" userUnit="GHz">250.0</prj:bandWidth>
                <prj:spectralResolution unit="kHz" userUnit="GHz">122.07031250000001</prj:spectralResolution>
                <prj:groupIndex>2</prj:groupIndex>
                <prj:isSkyFrequency>false</prj:isSkyFrequency>
                <prj:splatalogId>496163</prj:splatalogId>
                <prj:representativeWindow>false</prj:representativeWindow>
            </prj:ScienceSpectralWindow>
            <prj:ScienceSpectralWindow groupResourceUse="HALF">
                <prj:index>1</prj:index>
                <prj:AdvancedWindowSetup smoothingFunction="HANNING">
                    <prj:smoothingFactor>16</prj:smoothingFactor>
                    <prj:oversampling>false</prj:oversampling>
                    <prj:addedSensitivity>false</prj:addedSensitivity>
                    <prj:useImage>false</prj:useImage>
                    <prj:useThis>true</prj:useThis>
                </prj:AdvancedWindowSetup>
                <prj:transitionName>CS v=0 5-4</prj:transitionName>
                <prj:centerFrequency unit="GHz">244.93555600000002</prj:centerFrequency>
                <prj:bandWidth unit="MHz" userUnit="GHz">250.0</prj:bandWidth>
                <prj:spectralResolution unit="kHz" userUnit="GHz">122.07031250000001</prj:spectralResolution>
                <prj:groupIndex>2</prj:groupIndex>
                <prj:isSkyFrequency>false</prj:isSkyFrequency>
                <prj:splatalogId>3768801</prj:splatalogId>
                <prj:representativeWindow>false</prj:representativeWindow>
            </prj:ScienceSpectralWindow>
            <prj:ScienceSpectralWindow groupResourceUse="FULL">
                <prj:index>0</prj:index>
                <prj:AdvancedWindowSetup smoothingFunction="HANNING">
                    <prj:smoothingFactor>1</prj:smoothingFactor>
                    <prj:oversampling>false</prj:oversampling>
                    <prj:addedSensitivity>false</prj:addedSensitivity>
                    <prj:useImage>false</prj:useImage>
                    <prj:useThis>true</prj:useThis>
                </prj:AdvancedWindowSetup>
                <prj:transitionName>Continuum</prj:transitionName>
                <prj:centerFrequency unit="GHz">243.08108312155122</prj:centerFrequency>
                <prj:bandWidth unit="MHz" userUnit="GHz">2000.0</prj:bandWidth>
                <prj:spectralResolution unit="MHz" userUnit="GHz">15.625</prj:spectralResolution>
                <prj:groupIndex>3</prj:groupIndex>
                <prj:isSkyFrequency>false</prj:isSkyFrequency>
                <prj:representativeWindow>false</prj:representativeWindow>
            </prj:ScienceSpectralWindow>
            <prj:ScienceSpectralWindow groupResourceUse="FULL">
                <prj:index>0</prj:index>
                <prj:AdvancedWindowSetup smoothingFunction="HANNING">
                    <prj:smoothingFactor>16</prj:smoothingFactor>
                    <prj:oversampling>false</prj:oversampling>
                    <prj:addedSensitivity>false</prj:addedSensitivity>
                    <prj:useImage>false</prj:useImage>
                    <prj:useThis>true</prj:useThis>
                </prj:AdvancedWindowSetup>
                <prj:transitionName>CN v=0 N=2-1, J=5/2-3/2, F=7/2-5/2</prj:transitionName>
                <prj:centerFrequency unit="GHz">226.8747813</prj:centerFrequency>
                <prj:bandWidth unit="MHz" userUnit="GHz">500.0</prj:bandWidth>
                <prj:spectralResolution unit="kHz" userUnit="GHz">122.07031250000001</prj:spectralResolution>
                <prj:groupIndex>1</prj:groupIndex>
                <prj:isSkyFrequency>false</prj:isSkyFrequency>
                <prj:splatalogId>28188</prj:splatalogId>
                <prj:representativeWindow>false</prj:representativeWindow>
            </prj:ScienceSpectralWindow>
            <prj:ScienceSpectralWindow groupResourceUse="FULL">
                <prj:index>0</prj:index>
                <prj:AdvancedWindowSetup smoothingFunction="HANNING">
                    <prj:smoothingFactor>16</prj:smoothingFactor>
                    <prj:oversampling>false</prj:oversampling>
                    <prj:addedSensitivity>false</prj:addedSensitivity>
                    <prj:useImage>false</prj:useImage>
                    <prj:useThis>true</prj:useThis>
                </prj:AdvancedWindowSetup>
                <prj:transitionName>CO v=0 2-1</prj:transitionName>
                <prj:centerFrequency unit="GHz">230.538</prj:centerFrequency>
                <prj:bandWidth unit="MHz" userUnit="GHz">500.0</prj:bandWidth>
                <prj:spectralResolution unit="kHz" userUnit="GHz">122.07031250000001</prj:spectralResolution>
                <prj:groupIndex>0</prj:groupIndex>
                <prj:isSkyFrequency>false</prj:isSkyFrequency>
                <prj:splatalogId>3768101</prj:splatalogId>
                <prj:representativeWindow>true</prj:representativeWindow>
            </prj:ScienceSpectralWindow>
        </prj:SpectralSetupParameters>
        <prj:TargetParameters solarSystemObject="Unspecified" type="F_MultiplePoints">
            <prj:sourceName>v1362_aql</prj:sourceName>
            <prj:sourceCoordinates system="J2000" type="ABSOLUTE">
                <val:longitude unit="deg">282.174625</val:longitude>
                <val:latitude unit="deg">-2.841194</val:latitude>
                <val:fieldName>None</val:fieldName>
            </prj:sourceCoordinates>
            <prj:pmRA unit="mas/yr">0.0</prj:pmRA>
            <prj:pmDec unit="mas/yr">0.0</prj:pmDec>
            <prj:parallax unit="mas">0.0</prj:parallax>
            <prj:nonSiderealMotion>false</prj:nonSiderealMotion>
            <prj:sourceEphemeris></prj:sourceEphemeris>
            <prj:sourceVelocity referenceSystem="lsrk" dopplerCalcType="RADIO">
                <val:centerVelocity unit="km/s">100.0</val:centerVelocity>
            </prj:sourceVelocity>
            <prj:index>-1</prj:index>
            <prj:ExpectedProperties>
                <prj:expectedPeakFluxDensity unit="mJy">0.09</prj:expectedPeakFluxDensity>
                <prj:desiredPolarizationPercentage>0.0</prj:desiredPolarizationPercentage>
                <prj:expectedLineWidth unit="GHz" userUnit="km/s">0.02756163480215316</prj:expectedLineWidth>
                <prj:referenceFrequency unit="GHz">230.4611008006212</prj:referenceFrequency>
                <prj:expectedPeakLineFluxDensity unit="mJy">5.0</prj:expectedPeakLineFluxDensity>
                <prj:expectedSpectralDynamicRange>0.0</prj:expectedSpectralDynamicRange>
                <prj:expectedImageDynamicRange>0.0</prj:expectedImageDynamicRange>
                <prj:desiredLinePolarizationPercentage>0.0</prj:desiredLinePolarizationPercentage>
            </prj:ExpectedProperties>
            <prj:isMosaic>false</prj:isMosaic>
            <prj:SinglePoint>
                <prj:name></prj:name>
                <prj:centre system="J2000" type="RELATIVE">
                    <val:longitude unit="arcsec">0.0</val:longitude>
                    <val:latitude unit="arcsec">0.0</val:latitude>
                    <val:fieldName>v1362_aql-1</val:fieldName>
                </prj:centre>
            </prj:SinglePoint>
        </prj:TargetParameters>
        <prj:TechnicalJustification>
            <prj:justificationText>The correlator setup is focused on the primary goals of detecting 
- spatially resolved CO J=2-1 line emission
- dust continuum emission

Hence, one baseband is set for the CO J=2-1 line and one baseband is set for the dust continuum (at the lowest possible spectral resolution). The two extra basebands are set for additional science, i.e. a line of HNO and of CN (to constrain photodissociation models of AGB winds).

The CO J=2-1 line has 14 spectral resolution elements per line width. The main goal is to detect the line and spatially resolve it. The spectral structure is not expected to be complex (as derived from single-dish observations), so we ask for a spectral resolution that resolves the overall line shape. We also ask for the maximum spectral averaging to keep the data rate low. The window width of ~600 km/s provides enough continuum, given that the line width is known to be 36 km/s (for a wind expansion velocity of 18 km/s).

The additional-science line of CN has not been detected before and the deep integration required for the CO line, ensures that these observations provide reliable upper limits, if not detections. A low spectral resolution is enough, and ensures highest likelihood of detection. Finally, one SO line and one CS line are included in the spectral setup as they are common molecules in AGB outflows, but have not yet been observed in this OH30.1-0.7. </prj:justificationText>
            <prj:justificationKey>ED_CORRELATOR</prj:justificationKey>
        </prj:TechnicalJustification>
        <prj:TechnicalJustification>
            <prj:justificationText>The CO J=2-1 line is our primary concern for this science goal. We base the requested angular scales on:
1) the predicted superwind radii from the literature (going from r = 1700 AU up to r &gt; 6000 AU, i.e. diameters going from 3400 AU up to d &gt; 12000 AU)
2) the line formation region, estimated from 1d and 3d radiative-transfer models

To resolve the superwind radii, we need a beam size of at least 3400 AU. This is balanced by the need to detect weak emission in the outer parts of the wind. Because the size of the superwind itself, and not the structure within the superwind, is the primary goal, we request beam sizes so that the minimum resolution of the superwind on the sky is 4 in the worst case scenario of large distance and smallest predicted superwind size. Hence, we request the beam size equivalent of 1700 AU.

From radiative transfer models, the emission for the CO J=2-1 is predicted to be too weak to be detected beyond a radius of at least 10000 AU. To ensure we do not miss out on any flux at larger distances, we request a maximum recoverable scale of 20000 AU (diameter = 2*r = 2*10000 AU). 

To convert these numbers to angular scales, we take into account the uncertain distance to the source. The distance from SED modelling is estimated to be 2.0-2.4 kpc. The distance from 1612-MHz OH maser phase lag measurements is estimated to be ~4.0 kpc. 

Resolution:
- At 2.0 kpc, 1700 AU is 850 mas.
- At 4.0 kpc, 1700 AU is 425 mas.
We request 425 mas angular resolution.

Largest scale: 
- At 2.0 kpc, 20000 AU is 10 arcsec.
- At 4.0 kpc, 20000 AU is 5 arcsec.
We request a maximum recoverable scale of 10 arcsec.

The requested angular scales also allow to resolve the dust component of the superwind, and thus determine the superwind size in the dust. 

Additional science:
The spatial resolution of the CO emission drives the chosen angular scales. For all of the additional science (molecular lines), detection is the main goal. We do not expect to resolve this emission with the requested setting, and don't need to. 

Background:
The source lies in the galactic plane and is therefore affected by interstellar background contamination. However, the interstellar background is expected to be homogeneous on a scale of 40 arcseconds, based on position-switching IRAM observations with 20 arcseconds offset in four directions with respect to the source. ALMA observations should not be affected, as this background will be resolved out.</prj:justificationText>
            <prj:justificationKey>ED_ANGULAR_RESOLUTION</prj:justificationKey>
        </prj:TechnicalJustification>
        <prj:TechnicalJustification>
            <prj:justificationText>The expected flux density is estimated from 3D radiative transfer models that reproduce the single-dish and Herschel PACS and SPIRE for CO lines. The goal is 1) to constrain the size of the superwind by looking at emission in the outer wind compared to the emission in the inner wind, and 2) distinguish between variable mass-loss history and photodissociation in the wind by combining the measured photodissociation radius in CO J=1-0 with resolved dust continuum observations in Band 6. 

Three scenarios were tested: 
1) continuous high mass-loss-rate superwind
2) a tenuous lower mass-loss-rate wind increasing to a high, current mass-loss-rate superwind
3) continuous high mass-loss-rate superwind, with enhanced photodissociation

The density profiles associated with these three scenarios are:
1) a smooth r^-2 density profile
2) a smooth r^-2 density profile with a density decrease by one order of magnitude at 3375 AU
3) a smooth r^-2 density profile, cut off at a much closer distance from the stellar surface

To take into account several model dependencies, especially in scenario 2, we have always assumed worst-case scenarios in terms of flux contrast between high and low mass-loss-rate regimes, as well as the radius at which the density decreases. The goal is then to reach sensitivities that detect flux in the outer wind in scenario 1, but not in scenario 2. 

For CO J=2-1 in scenario 1, predicted flux estimates are:
- at the density step radius of 3375 AU: 60 mJy/beam
- in the outer wind at r &gt; 3375 AU, smooth decrease from 60 mJy/beam to 5 mJy/beam
using a synthesised beam size of 0.425''. In scenarios 2 and 3, the flux in the outer wind would simply not be detected. The predicted flux at the midpoint of the image is 370 mJy/beam.

To detect the emission from the outer wind far enough (up to 10000 AU - see justification angular scales), we request a sensitivity of 1.20 mJy. This leads to an SNR of 4 for the outermost parts of the wind that are still detectable, and higher SNR at r &lt; 10000 AU. 

The bandwidth of the CO J=2-1 line is used in the sensitivity calculation. The spectral resolution does not have to be high, since the goal is to detect the line and spatially resolve it. The line is not expected to show any complex spectral structure, as shown by single-dish observations. 14 spectral resolution elements is therefore enough, and allows a higher detection limit.

For the other lines in this spectral setup, spatial resolution is not important, and a 3-sigma detection of the central component is enough to reach the additional science goals. Since we already perform a deep integration for the tenuous CO 2-1 emission, the other lines are likely to be detected if they are sufficiently abundant (in the case of the chemical daughter species CN, or in the case of SO and CS). 

The peak continuum flux density is estimated from dust radiative-transfer models reproducing the SED of the source. Images were calculated at 1.3 mm, and ray-traced according to a resolution equivalent with the synthesised beam size of 0.425 arcsec. The peak of the flux distribution results in estimated fluxes of:
- 1.9 mJy/beam for scenario 1
- 1.3 mJy/beam for scenario 2 and 3
The requested sensitivity for the CO J=2-1 line is high enough to detect the continuum emission. This places strong constraints on the long-wavelength fluxes of this source, which were not available before without interstellar background contamination. 

In addition, at 1.7 arcseconds from the center of the image, the dust emission amounts to
- 0.09 mJy/beam for scenario 1
- 0.007 mJy/beam for scenario 2 and 3
With the requested sensitivity of the CO J=2-1 line, we can still detect continuum flux 1.7 arcsec from the central source in scenario 1, while a non-detection would result from scenarios 2 and 3. This constrains the size of the dust component of the superwind, and therefore distinguishes between scenarios 2 and 3. Hence, we request a continuum flux density of 0.09 mJy/beam.</prj:justificationText>
            <prj:justificationKey>ED_SENSITIVITY</prj:justificationKey>
        </prj:TechnicalJustification>
    </prj:ScienceGoal>
    <prj:ObsPlan status="NewPhase2" entityPartId="X2062654284" almatype="APDM::ObsUnitSet">
        <prj:name>ObsUnitSet</prj:name>
        <prj:note></prj:note>
        <prj:ObsUnitControl arrayRequested="TWELVE-M">
            <prj:maximumTime unit="min">0.0</prj:maximumTime>
            <prj:userPriority>0</prj:userPriority>
            <prj:estimatedExecutionTime unit="min">0.0</prj:estimatedExecutionTime>
            <prj:tacPriority>0</prj:tacPriority>
            <prj:aggregatedExecutionCount>0</prj:aggregatedExecutionCount>
            <prj:CalibrationRequirements>
                <prj:pointingAccuracy unit="arcsec">0.0</prj:pointingAccuracy>
            </prj:CalibrationRequirements>
        </prj:ObsUnitControl>
        <prj:scienceProcessingScript></prj:scienceProcessingScript>
        <prj:runSciencePipeline>false</prj:runSciencePipeline>
    </prj:ObsPlan>
    <prp:ObsProposalEntity entityId="uid://A001/X198/X1b"
        entityIdEncrypted="-- id encryption not implemented --"
        entityTypeName="ObsProposal" schemaVersion="13"
        documentVersion="1" timestamp="2015-04-23T08:32:28.274"/>
    <prp:DocumentsRef entityId="uid://A001/X198/X1c"
        entityTypeName="ObsAttachment" documentVersion="1"/>
    <prp:ObsProjectRef entityId="uid://A001/X198/X1a"
        entityTypeName="ObsProject" documentVersion="1"/>
    <prp:abstract>Our understanding of the late stages of evolution of 5-8 solar-mass stars on the asymptotic giant branch has been challenged. For over 30 years, the hypothesis was that a high mass-loss-rate superwind of several 10^-4 solar masses per year for ten thousands of years allows these OH/IR stars to evolve into white dwarfs. However, recent modeling of single-dish (sub)mm observations predicts much shorter durations for the superwind phenomenon. This implies that these stars need to lose several solar masses by means other than one superwind. Alternatively, some mechanism is destroying the diagnostics commonly used to study the superwind at closer distances to the star than expected, e.g. enhanced photodissociation of CO by the interstellar UV radiation field.

We propose a study on the superwind of the OH/IR star OH30.1-0.7, the first of its kind to be observed with ALMA. By measuring the spatial distribution of CO and dust emission we constrain the mass-loss history and CO photodissociation radius. Using ALMA's unprecedented sensitivity and spatial resolution we can conclusively distinguish which of these two processes is the main cause of the (appearance of the) small-sized superwind.</prp:abstract>
    <prp:relatedProposals></prp:relatedProposals>
    <prp:previousProposals>Project 2013.1.00445.S: The evolutionary conundrum of the intermediate-mass oxygen-rich asymptotic-giant-branch stars</prp:previousProposals>
    <prp:dateReceived>2015-04-23T08:32:27.409Z</prp:dateReceived>
    <prp:cycle>2015.1</prp:cycle>
    <prp:scientificCategoryCode>50</prp:scientificCategoryCode>
    <prp:proposalTypeCode>S</prp:proposalTypeCode>
    <prp:scientificCategoryString>Stellar Evolution and the Sun</prp:scientificCategoryString>
    <prp:proposalTypeString>Standard</prp:proposalTypeString>
    <prp:keyword>Asymptotic Giant Branch (AGB) stars</prp:keyword>
    <prp:keyword>Evolved stars - Shaping/physical structure</prp:keyword>
    <prp:keywordCode>50c</prp:keywordCode>
    <prp:keywordCode>50f</prp:keywordCode>
    <prp:PrincipalInvestigator allowedExec="EU" associatedExec="EU">
        <prp:fullName>Robin Lombaert</prp:fullName>
        <prp:organisation>Institute of Astronomy, Leuven, Catholic University</prp:organisation>
        <prp:eMail>robin.lombaert@ster.kuleuven.be</prp:eMail>
        <prp:verfiedUser>true</prp:verfiedUser>
        <prp:userId>robinlombaert</prp:userId>
        <prp:telephone></prp:telephone>
        <prp:mobile></prp:mobile>
        <prp:index>1</prp:index>
        <prp:organisationId>21026</prp:organisationId>
    </prp:PrincipalInvestigator>
    <prp:CoInvestigator allowedExec="EU" associatedExec="EU">
        <prp:fullName>Matthias Maercker</prp:fullName>
        <prp:organisation>Onsala Space Observatory, Chalmers University of Technology</prp:organisation>
        <prp:eMail>maercker@chalmers.se</prp:eMail>
        <prp:verfiedUser>true</prp:verfiedUser>
        <prp:userId>maercker</prp:userId>
        <prp:telephone></prp:telephone>
        <prp:mobile></prp:mobile>
        <prp:index>1</prp:index>
        <prp:organisationId>21257</prp:organisationId>
    </prp:CoInvestigator>
    <prp:CoInvestigator allowedExec="EU" associatedExec="EU">
        <prp:fullName>Elvire De Beck</prp:fullName>
        <prp:organisation>Onsala Space Observatory, Chalmers University of Technology</prp:organisation>
        <prp:eMail>elvire.debeck@chalmers.se</prp:eMail>
        <prp:verfiedUser>true</prp:verfiedUser>
        <prp:userId>elviredebeck</prp:userId>
        <prp:telephone></prp:telephone>
        <prp:mobile></prp:mobile>
        <prp:index>1</prp:index>
        <prp:organisationId>21257</prp:organisationId>
    </prp:CoInvestigator>
    <prp:CoInvestigator allowedExec="EU" associatedExec="EU">
        <prp:fullName>Theo Khouri</prp:fullName>
        <prp:organisation>Onsala Space Observatory, Chalmers University of Technology</prp:organisation>
        <prp:eMail>theokhouri@gmail.com</prp:eMail>
        <prp:verfiedUser>true</prp:verfiedUser>
        <prp:userId>theokhouri</prp:userId>
        <prp:telephone></prp:telephone>
        <prp:mobile></prp:mobile>
        <prp:index>1</prp:index>
        <prp:organisationId>21257</prp:organisationId>
    </prp:CoInvestigator>
    <prp:CoInvestigator allowedExec="EU" associatedExec="EU">
        <prp:fullName>Marie Van de Sande</prp:fullName>
        <prp:organisation>Institute of Astronomy, KU Leuven</prp:organisation>
        <prp:eMail>marie.vandesande@ster.kuleuven.be</prp:eMail>
        <prp:verfiedUser>true</prp:verfiedUser>
        <prp:userId>marievds</prp:userId>
        <prp:telephone></prp:telephone>
        <prp:mobile></prp:mobile>
        <prp:index>1</prp:index>
        <prp:organisationId>35061</prp:organisationId>
    </prp:CoInvestigator>
    <prp:CoInvestigator allowedExec="EU" associatedExec="EU">
        <prp:fullName>Ward Homan</prp:fullName>
        <prp:organisation>Institute of Astronomy, Leuven, Catholic University</prp:organisation>
        <prp:eMail>ward.homan@ster.kuleuven.be</prp:eMail>
        <prp:verfiedUser>true</prp:verfiedUser>
        <prp:userId>wardhoman</prp:userId>
        <prp:telephone></prp:telephone>
        <prp:mobile></prp:mobile>
        <prp:index>1</prp:index>
        <prp:organisationId>21026</prp:organisationId>
    </prp:CoInvestigator>
    <prp:CoInvestigator allowedExec="EU" associatedExec="EU">
        <prp:fullName>Rutger De Nutte</prp:fullName>
        <prp:organisation>Institute of Astronomy, KU Leuven</prp:organisation>
        <prp:eMail>rutger.denutte@ster.kuleuven.be</prp:eMail>
        <prp:verfiedUser>true</prp:verfiedUser>
        <prp:userId>rdenutte</prp:userId>
        <prp:telephone></prp:telephone>
        <prp:mobile></prp:mobile>
        <prp:index>1</prp:index>
        <prp:organisationId>35061</prp:organisationId>
    </prp:CoInvestigator>
    <prp:CoInvestigator allowedExec="EU" associatedExec="EU">
        <prp:fullName>Taissa Danilovich</prp:fullName>
        <prp:organisation>Onsala Space Observatory, Chalmers University of Technology</prp:organisation>
        <prp:eMail>taissa@chalmers.se</prp:eMail>
        <prp:verfiedUser>true</prp:verfiedUser>
        <prp:userId>taissa</prp:userId>
        <prp:telephone></prp:telephone>
        <prp:mobile></prp:mobile>
        <prp:index>1</prp:index>
        <prp:organisationId>21257</prp:organisationId>
    </prp:CoInvestigator>
    <prp:CoInvestigator allowedExec="EU" associatedExec="EU">
        <prp:fullName>Alex de Koter</prp:fullName>
        <prp:organisation>Astronomical Institute Anton Pannekoek, University of Amsterdam</prp:organisation>
        <prp:eMail>a.dekoter@uva.nl</prp:eMail>
        <prp:verfiedUser>true</prp:verfiedUser>
        <prp:userId>adekoter</prp:userId>
        <prp:telephone></prp:telephone>
        <prp:mobile></prp:mobile>
        <prp:index>1</prp:index>
        <prp:organisationId>21215</prp:organisationId>
    </prp:CoInvestigator>
    <prp:CoInvestigator allowedExec="EU" associatedExec="EU">
        <prp:fullName>Leen Decin</prp:fullName>
        <prp:organisation>Institute of Astronomy, Leuven, Catholic University</prp:organisation>
        <prp:eMail>Leen.Decin@ster.kuleuven.be</prp:eMail>
        <prp:verfiedUser>true</prp:verfiedUser>
        <prp:userId>ldecin</prp:userId>
        <prp:telephone></prp:telephone>
        <prp:mobile></prp:mobile>
        <prp:index>1</prp:index>
        <prp:organisationId>21026</prp:organisationId>
    </prp:CoInvestigator>
    <prp:CoInvestigator allowedExec="EU" associatedExec="EU">
        <prp:fullName>Laurens Waters</prp:fullName>
        <prp:organisation>SRON Utrecht, SRON Netherlands Institute for Space Research</prp:organisation>
        <prp:eMail>waters@sron.nl</prp:eMail>
        <prp:verfiedUser>true</prp:verfiedUser>
        <prp:userId>waters</prp:userId>
        <prp:telephone></prp:telephone>
        <prp:mobile></prp:mobile>
        <prp:index>1</prp:index>
        <prp:organisationId>21213</prp:organisationId>
    </prp:CoInvestigator>
    <prp:CoInvestigator allowedExec="EU" associatedExec="EU">
        <prp:fullName>Richard Stancliffe</prp:fullName>
        <prp:organisation>Argelander-Institute for Astronomy, Bonn University</prp:organisation>
        <prp:eMail>rjstancl@astro.uni-bonn.de</prp:eMail>
        <prp:verfiedUser>true</prp:verfiedUser>
        <prp:userId>rstancliffe</prp:userId>
        <prp:telephone></prp:telephone>
        <prp:mobile></prp:mobile>
        <prp:index>1</prp:index>
        <prp:organisationId>21108</prp:organisationId>
    </prp:CoInvestigator>
    <prp:CoInvestigator allowedExec="EU" associatedExec="EU">
        <prp:fullName>Wouter Vlemmings</prp:fullName>
        <prp:organisation>Onsala Space Observatory, Chalmers University of Technology</prp:organisation>
        <prp:eMail>wouter.vlemmings@chalmers.se</prp:eMail>
        <prp:verfiedUser>true</prp:verfiedUser>
        <prp:userId>wvlemmings</prp:userId>
        <prp:telephone></prp:telephone>
        <prp:mobile></prp:mobile>
        <prp:index>1</prp:index>
        <prp:organisationId>21257</prp:organisationId>
    </prp:CoInvestigator>
    <prp:CoInvestigator allowedExec="EU" associatedExec="EU">
        <prp:fullName>Pierre Royer</prp:fullName>
        <prp:organisation>Institute of Astronomy, Leuven, Catholic University</prp:organisation>
        <prp:eMail>pierre@ster.kuleuven.be</prp:eMail>
        <prp:verfiedUser>true</prp:verfiedUser>
        <prp:userId>proyer</prp:userId>
        <prp:telephone></prp:telephone>
        <prp:mobile></prp:mobile>
        <prp:index>1</prp:index>
        <prp:organisationId>21026</prp:organisationId>
    </prp:CoInvestigator>
    <prp:CoInvestigator allowedExec="EU" associatedExec="EU">
        <prp:fullName>Michel Hillen</prp:fullName>
        <prp:organisation>Institute of Astronomy, Leuven, Catholic University</prp:organisation>
        <prp:eMail>michelh@ster.kuleuven.be</prp:eMail>
        <prp:verfiedUser>true</prp:verfiedUser>
        <prp:userId>michelh</prp:userId>
        <prp:telephone></prp:telephone>
        <prp:mobile></prp:mobile>
        <prp:index>1</prp:index>
        <prp:organisationId>21026</prp:organisationId>
    </prp:CoInvestigator>
    <prp:CoInvestigator allowedExec="EU" associatedExec="EU">
        <prp:fullName>Jonathan Menu</prp:fullName>
        <prp:organisation>Institute of Astronomy, Leuven, Catholic University</prp:organisation>
        <prp:eMail>jonathan.menu@ster.kuleuven.be</prp:eMail>
        <prp:verfiedUser>true</prp:verfiedUser>
        <prp:userId>jmenu</prp:userId>
        <prp:telephone></prp:telephone>
        <prp:mobile></prp:mobile>
        <prp:index>1</prp:index>
        <prp:organisationId>21026</prp:organisationId>
    </prp:CoInvestigator>
    <prp:CoInvestigator allowedExec="EU" associatedExec="EU">
        <prp:fullName>Bernard de Vries</prp:fullName>
        <prp:organisation>AlbaNova University Center, Stockholm University</prp:organisation>
        <prp:eMail>bldevries.science@gmail.com</prp:eMail>
        <prp:verfiedUser>true</prp:verfiedUser>
        <prp:userId>bldevries</prp:userId>
        <prp:telephone></prp:telephone>
        <prp:mobile></prp:mobile>
        <prp:index>1</prp:index>
        <prp:organisationId>21265</prp:organisationId>
    </prp:CoInvestigator>
    <prp:CoInvestigator allowedExec="EU" associatedExec="EU">
        <prp:fullName>Nick Cox</prp:fullName>
        <prp:organisation>Institute of Research in Astrophysics and Planetology</prp:organisation>
        <prp:eMail>nick.cox@irap.omp.eu</prp:eMail>
        <prp:verfiedUser>true</prp:verfiedUser>
        <prp:userId>ncox</prp:userId>
        <prp:telephone></prp:telephone>
        <prp:mobile></prp:mobile>
        <prp:index>1</prp:index>
        <prp:organisationId>35034</prp:organisationId>
    </prp:CoInvestigator>
    <prp:CoInvestigator allowedExec="EU" associatedExec="EU">
        <prp:fullName>Franz Kerschbaum</prp:fullName>
        <prp:organisation>Institute of Astronomy, Vienna, University of</prp:organisation>
        <prp:eMail>franz.kerschbaum@univie.ac.at</prp:eMail>
        <prp:verfiedUser>true</prp:verfiedUser>
        <prp:userId>fkerschbaum</prp:userId>
        <prp:telephone></prp:telephone>
        <prp:mobile></prp:mobile>
        <prp:index>1</prp:index>
        <prp:organisationId>21021</prp:organisationId>
    </prp:CoInvestigator>
    <prp:CoInvestigator allowedExec="EU" associatedExec="EU">
        <prp:fullName>Claudia Paladini</prp:fullName>
        <prp:organisation>Institute of Astronomy and Astrophysics (IAA), Universite libre de Bruxelles (ULB)</prp:organisation>
        <prp:eMail>paladini@ulb.ac.be</prp:eMail>
        <prp:verfiedUser>true</prp:verfiedUser>
        <prp:userId>cpaladini</prp:userId>
        <prp:telephone></prp:telephone>
        <prp:mobile></prp:mobile>
        <prp:index>1</prp:index>
        <prp:organisationId>21030</prp:organisationId>
    </prp:CoInvestigator>
    <prp:CoInvestigator allowedExec="EU" associatedExec="EU">
        <prp:fullName>Joris Blommaert</prp:fullName>
        <prp:organisation>Institute of Astronomy, Leuven, Catholic University</prp:organisation>
        <prp:eMail>jorisb@ster.kuleuven.be</prp:eMail>
        <prp:verfiedUser>true</prp:verfiedUser>
        <prp:userId>jblommaert</prp:userId>
        <prp:telephone></prp:telephone>
        <prp:mobile></prp:mobile>
        <prp:index>1</prp:index>
        <prp:organisationId>21026</prp:organisationId>
    </prp:CoInvestigator>
    <prp:ProposalFeedback>
        <prp:estimatedTotalIntegrationTime unit="s">19124.319999</prp:estimatedTotalIntegrationTime>
        <prp:ArrayTimeBreakdown>
            <prp:ArrayTime arrayName="ACA">
                <prp:estimatedTime unit="s">65295.319999</prp:estimatedTime>
            </prp:ArrayTime>
            <prp:ArrayTime arrayName="SEVEN-M">
                <prp:estimatedTime unit="s">34056.279999000006</prp:estimatedTime>
            </prp:ArrayTime>
            <prp:ArrayTime arrayName="TP-Array">
                <prp:estimatedTime unit="s">31239.04</prp:estimatedTime>
            </prp:ArrayTime>
            <prp:ArrayTime arrayName="TWELVE-M">
                <prp:estimatedTime unit="s">19124.319999</prp:estimatedTime>
            </prp:ArrayTime>
            <prp:ArrayTime arrayName="ALMA">
                <prp:estimatedTime unit="s">68800.12</prp:estimatedTime>
            </prp:ArrayTime>
        </prp:ArrayTimeBreakdown>
        <prp:DataRateBreakdown>
            <prp:ArrayDataRates arrayName="TWELVE-M">
                <prp:estimatedAverageDataRate unit="MB/s">1.2438249975099172</prp:estimatedAverageDataRate>
                <prp:estimatedMaximumDataRate unit="MB/s">1.3488846481161774</prp:estimatedMaximumDataRate>
                <prp:estimatedDataVolume unit="GB">11.682114219629957</prp:estimatedDataVolume>
            </prp:ArrayDataRates>
            <prp:ArrayDataRates arrayName="SEVEN-M">
                <prp:estimatedAverageDataRate unit="MB/s">0.5390235156151222</prp:estimatedAverageDataRate>
                <prp:estimatedMaximumDataRate unit="MB/s">0.5838038429381356</prp:estimatedMaximumDataRate>
                <prp:estimatedDataVolume unit="GB">12.55563818938625</prp:estimatedDataVolume>
            </prp:ArrayDataRates>
            <prp:ArrayDataRates arrayName="TP-Array">
                <prp:estimatedAverageDataRate unit="MB/s">0.030593266562810018</prp:estimatedAverageDataRate>
                <prp:estimatedMaximumDataRate unit="MB/s">0.030593266562810018</prp:estimatedMaximumDataRate>
                <prp:estimatedDataVolume unit="GB">0.34667911773461163</prp:estimatedDataVolume>
            </prp:ArrayDataRates>
        </prp:DataRateBreakdown>
        <prp:ReceiverTimeBreakdown>
            <prp:ReceiverTime receiverBand="ALMA_RB_03">
                <prp:time unit="s">7809.76</prp:time>
            </prp:ReceiverTime>
            <prp:ReceiverTime receiverBand="ALMA_RB_07">
                <prp:time unit="s">5026.02</prp:time>
            </prp:ReceiverTime>
            <prp:ReceiverTime receiverBand="ALMA_RB_06">
                <prp:time unit="s">6288.539999</prp:time>
            </prp:ReceiverTime>
        </prp:ReceiverTimeBreakdown>
        <prp:TimeAllocationBreakdown>
            <prp:ExecutiveFraction name="OTHER">
                <prp:timeFraction>0.0</prp:timeFraction>
            </prp:ExecutiveFraction>
            <prp:ExecutiveFraction name="CL">
                <prp:timeFraction>0.0</prp:timeFraction>
            </prp:ExecutiveFraction>
            <prp:ExecutiveFraction name="EA">
                <prp:timeFraction>0.0</prp:timeFraction>
            </prp:ExecutiveFraction>
            <prp:ExecutiveFraction name="EU">
                <prp:timeFraction>1.0</prp:timeFraction>
            </prp:ExecutiveFraction>
            <prp:ExecutiveFraction name="NA">
                <prp:timeFraction>0.0</prp:timeFraction>
            </prp:ExecutiveFraction>
            <prp:ExecutiveFraction name="NA_EA">
                <prp:timeFraction>0.0</prp:timeFraction>
            </prp:ExecutiveFraction>
        </prp:TimeAllocationBreakdown>
    </prp:ProposalFeedback>
</prp:ObsProposal>
